Benjamin Sampica

I currently work as a Web Application Developer for Polk County Administration in Des Moines and have been since June 2016.

I utilize the .NET stack with a focus on ASP.NET Core to build web applications that help Polk County better serve its residents. I also implemented and actively maintain our Azure DevOps CI/CD environments for a smooth transition from local development to

I graduated from the University of Northern lowa with a bachelor's degree in Management Information Systems in May of 2016. I also graduated in 2012 with an associate degree as a Computer Support Specialist.

See what I'm up to at www.bensampica.com

Professional Skills

Expert MVC Expert FF Core Expert Bootstrap 4 Expert Bootstrap 3 Advanced Azure DevOps Advanced C# Advanced .NFT Advanced LINO Advanced FF₅ Intermediate JIRA Intermediate CSS Intermediate **Javascript** Intermediate Git Intermediate MSSQL Intermediate

Freelance Projects

Angela Connolly - www.angelaconnolly.org

Built using MVC5, EF 5, and Bootstrap 3, Angela Connolly is Polk County's current Board of Supervisor for District 2.

It utilizes Facebook API to pull content directly from her public Facebook page and also links with ShareBlue, a fundraising organization for politicians.

The site received thousands of unique visitors and was responsible for tens of thousands of dollars in donations during the 2018 election. After the election was won the site was

Hobbies & Interests

Computers

I'm a hardware enthusiast at heart and enjoy following the computer hardware scene. I've custom built dozens of computers over the years and each time I try to one-up myself.

I've been playing racquetball since my dad got me into it over a decade ago. It's great exercise and I love the dynamic challenge of speed, skill, and strategy. I also run the IMT and Dam to Dam half marathons in Des Moines.

Education

University of Northern Iowa Management Information Systems

Cedar Falls Iowa Graduated May 2016

Officer of UNIPAWWSH (charity group). Officer of UNISTARR (Student rights group).

Kirkwood Community College Computer Support Specialist Cedar Rapids Iowa Graduated December 2012

Employment History

Polk County Web Application Developer Des Moines Iowa

June 2016 - Present

- I am first a full-stack developer starting with gathering requirements/existing workflows through front-end implementation with client acceptance.
- I contribute in the architecture and maintenance of a 'base' web application solution with the latest development standards, patterns, and frameworks so that other developers on my team can jump start their projects faster.
- I am an agent of change via boots on the ground work such
- -- Implement and lead a technical talk, where developers choose a topic and deep-dive into it for an hour.
- -- Leading and managing the sprint retrospective and reviews as we are short a scrum master.
- I also drive architectural decisions such as:
- Changing our development stack from JIRA/Bitbucket to Azure DevOps. I administrate the organization-level duties such as managing deployment groups and team permissions, but also dive into low-level programming duties like creating a base template pipeline with which all of our web solutions and nuget libraries can use.
- API strategy for our organization, of which is a relatively unexplored direction for Polk County, to share data between business applications as well as other parts of the organization.
- Most importantly, I help others and maintain good relationships with my coworkers. I keep a stack of architecture, pattern, devops, programming, and soft-skill craftsman books at my desk for others to 'check-out' and read themselves. My coworkers, who are my friends, are not afraid to approach me with any type of question.

The Members Group IT Service Coordinator

Urbandale Iowa

January 2016 - June 2016

- Took Help Desk Support calls and logged tickets.
- Resolved Tier 1 Tier 3 (Non-Application Development)
- Trained incoming Tier 1 employees on common issues and application-specific workflows.

IT Intern

Urbandale Iowa

May 2015 - August 2015

- Updated, created, and maintained company SharePoint sites.
- Led project to create a SharePoint consistency template among team sites.
- Created automation scripts with Selenium in Java for largescale automation testing.
- Wrote documentation for SharePoint from both a users and developers point of view.
- Updated VBA-based software to improve search accuracy and added in new systems.



